<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Omar Valdez | The Data Fixer</title>
    <link>https://thedatafixer.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Omar Valdez | The Data Fixer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thedatafixer.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why being a Data Architect?</title>
      <link>https://thedatafixer.xyz/posts/why-being-a-data-architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedatafixer.xyz/posts/why-being-a-data-architect/</guid>
      <description>It is very important that data is accessible and reusable for society and industry. Nowadays, it is crucial that data has the capacity to be accessible and reusable not only for the workforce but also for regular users, such as someone using social media and trying to download their own information.
Creating, saving, ingesting, transforming, processing, and visualizing data are tasks that require time and effort. Additionally, maintaining security, executing administration, performing operations, detailing orchestration, preserving good software engineering practices, and defining data architecture strategy are extremely critical aspects of the data ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[~] $ whoami</title>
      <link>https://thedatafixer.xyz/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedatafixer.xyz/whoami/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Omar Valdez.
My purpose is to share my knowledge with the community interested in the fascinating world of data, and my goal is to encompass the entire data lifecycle ecosystem, from generation to deployment. Additionally, I want to highlight the key elements that underlie the data lifecycle, such as security, data management, DataOps (data operations), data architecture, orchestration, and software engineering.
What I will NOT talk about:
I will not focus on general topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data for Dummies</title>
      <link>https://thedatafixer.xyz/datafordummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedatafixer.xyz/datafordummies/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever felt overwhelmed by terms like Data Lake, metadata, or Data Governance, then you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. I know that even for the same concept, there can be different interpretations, so my intention is not to define but to explain the word in a simple way, accompanied by an example or context.
If you think something should be added or edited, you can leave a comment at the end of this post, or you can also contact me in whichever way is most convenient for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
